{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Instrument transformers are classified as:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Potential transformer",
        "b": "Current transformer",
        "c": "Both Potential transformer and Current transformer",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Potential transformers are made with",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Low quality icon core operating at very low flex density so that the magnetizing current may be large",
        "b": "High quality icon core operating at very high flex density so that the magnetizing current may be large",
        "c": "High quality icon core operating at very high flex density so that the magnetizing current may be very small",
        "d": "High quality icon core operating at very low flex density so that the magnetizing current may be very small"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Potential transformers are carefully designed to ensure",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Minimum variation of voltage ratio with load and minimum phase shift between input and output voltages",
        "b": "Minimum variation of voltage ratio with load and maximum phase shift between input and output voltages",
        "c": "Maximum variation of voltage ratio with load and maximum phase shift between input and output voltages",
        "d": "Maximum variation of voltage ratio with load and minimum phase shift between input and output voltages"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In a transformer, if N2 is number of secondary winding N1 is the number of primary winding then, if (N2/N1) ratio is lesser than 1.It is called as ________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Step down transformer",
        "b": "Step up transformer",
        "c": "Isolation transformer",
        "d": "All"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In an ideal transformer,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "There are no losses",
        "b": "Windings have zero resistance",
        "c": "Leakage flex is zero",
        "d": "All"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Oil transformer usually consist of,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "A conservator tank, buchholz relay",
        "b": "Breather of dehydrating type",
        "c": "Winding temperature-indicator, oil temperature indicator",
        "d": "Al"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "32 step tap changes provide ________ voltage change in each step.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "5/4 %",
        "b": "4/5 %",
        "c": "5/8%",
        "d": "8/5 %"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Conservator is an oil-expansion tank mounted _________ on the transformer.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Below the highest oil point",
        "b": "Ground level",
        "c": "Above the highest oil point",
        "d": "Any of them"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The function of __________ is to isolate the part of the power system in case of abnormal conditions.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Circuit Breaker",
        "b": "Isolator",
        "c": "Insulator",
        "d": "All"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Advantages of using Air blast Circuit breakers :",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Current chopping",
        "b": "Sensitivity to restricting voltage",
        "c": "Short arc duration",
        "d": "All"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "When low inductive current is interrupted by a Circuit breaker and the arc generating force of the Circuit breaker and is more than necessary to interrupt a low magnitude of current, the current will be interrupted before its natural zero instant. It is termed as",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Restriking",
        "b": "Recovery instant",
        "c": "Current chopping",
        "d": "Arcing voltage"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "_______ is the current (r.m.s value) that a Circuit breaker is capable of breaking under specified conditions and given recovery voltage",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Breaking capacity",
        "b": "Making capacity",
        "c": "Short-time capacity",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ of a Circuit breaker depends upon its ability to withstand the temperature rise and the electromagnetic force effects.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Breaking capacity",
        "b": "Making capacity",
        "c": "Short-time capacity",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Bus bar can be arranged in _________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Single bus-bar system",
        "b": "Double bus-bar system with sectionalisation",
        "c": "Both Single bus-bar system and Double bus-bar system with sectionalisation",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The major advantage of single bus-bar system is that fault on one part of the bus'bar or system does not completely shut down the whole station.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "False",
        "b": "True"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    }
  ]
}
